Windows Internet Name Service, or WINS, resolves NetBIOS names to IP addresses.
This was the common method used to resolve hostnames to IP addresses before DNS came to the forefront.
Nowadays, you only see WINS used basically on apps that were most likely built a long time ago and still use WINS.
Most of the time now, DNS is the preferred method of resolving hostnames to IP addresses.
We have established that DNS is the primary method of resolving host names to IP addresses.
For the exam and for real-life situations, it is important to know the order in which hostnames are resolved.
Here is that order:  Before looking at DNS, a host checks to see if the HOSTS file, which we will look at shortly, has a hostname to IP address mapping.
HOSTS files are used when a DNS entry is not available or wanted for resolving hostnames to IP addresses. The DNS server indicated under one's IP address profile is looked at next.
If there are multiple DNS servers listed, they will be tried, in order. If none of the local DNS server addresses resolve the name,
the query is forwarded until a DNS server with the matching IP address is found and then the information is returned to the source.